

# Elbert John Orozco

iOS Software Engineer

elbertorozco@protonmail.com

+639776801091

Ortigas Extension, Pasig City, Philippines

bytethenoodle.github.io

linkedin.com/in/elbert-john-orozco-14a110107 in

twitter.com/noodlebytes

github.com/bytethenoodle 🦪

instagram.com/elbert\_orozco 🧿

My overall objective is to learn, build, teach, and improve iOS apps with the latest trends in technology. I have been an iOS software developer since 2015 and is always very passionate in doing it. I am also a hobbyist doing "Internet-of-Things" experiments and other open source projects. I also have a keen interest in data science and to have iOS apps use these technologies for different things.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## iOS Developer

WINAS Technologies International Philippines Inc.

07/2019 - Present

Mandaluyong City

#### Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the team in features and diagnosing issues
- Assist in development of backend apis

# Software Developer (iOS)

**Amdocs Philippines** 

04/2018 - 06/2019

Pasig City

#### Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the support team and backend in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for mobile software development
- Assist in designing mockups using Adobe XD or Sketch (UI prototyping)
- Develop tools/helpers that will make development easier/faster
- Assist in app feature discussions with business to determine which is plausible or not

# Software Development Analyst (iOS)

**Smart Communications** 

Makati City

#### 12/2016 – 04/2018 **—** Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the support team in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for iOS Development

#### **SKILLS**



## **PROJECTS INVOLVED**

myPLDT Smart (2019)

PLDT Enterprise 177 app (2018) 🗷

Smart360 (2018)

Ka-Partner for Smart Retail (2018)

Smart Infinity (2017 - 2018) 🗗

mySmart app (2017 – 2019) 🗹

Talk n' Text app (2017) 🗹

"Acqui" app for Globe myBusiness (2016)

BookIt for iPhone (2016)

Unilab - PediaLink for iPhone (2015)

DOT - moreFun for iPhone/iPad (2015)

FunPH for iPhone/iPad (2015)

AgTech Apps for iPhone/iPad (2015) 🗗

Embedded System Spec Monitoring App (2015)

Arduino Based Oscilloscope Monitor for iPhone (2014)

Inventory System Application (2014)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# iOS Developer (Contract)

#### **Asticom Technologies**

06/2016 - 11/2016

Taguig City

- Tasks
- Develop internal mobile apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Translate requirements into functional app modules
- Assist the support team in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for iOS Development

# **Mobile Developer**

#### Rogomi Inc

07/2015 - 06/2016

Pasig City

- Tasks
- Gather requirements around functionality and translate those requirements into functional solutions
- Develop mobile applications on assigned platforms
- Assist the Technical Support team in diagnosing bugs and other issues in products
- Assist the QA team with new product releases and bug fixes for products
- Continuously study iOS and/or Android development
- Accomplish miscellaneous I.T.-related tasks

# Freelance (Design, Development, Research) Private Clients

10/2014 – 07/2015 Manila

- Tasks
- Completed embedded system and mobile applications development projects from various clients.
- Pursued personal research on different software platforms such as for the open source Mono .NET project for both desktop and mobile applications, the Arduino, and Raspberry Pi for embedded systems and IOT (Internet-of-Things)
- Research on SQL and PHP class wrappers for iOS and Java Android

#### On-The-Job Trainee

#### Philippine Long Distance Telephone

10/2014 - 01/2015

Marikina City

- Task
- Assigned to work as a Main Distribution Frame Assistant checking for telephone connection faults to and from the central office
- Assigned to work as a Local Customer Database Verifier verifying customer accounts to its corresponding port number assignments in the central office in a local database

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer

## **AMA Computer College**

01/2014 - 09/2014

Antipolo City

Tasks

- Served as one of the developers of an iOS application that displays the information sent wirelessly by an Arduino-Based oscilloscope as part of a school research programme
- Helped the school student development team that completed a revised implementation of an Inventory System Application for employee time sheets written in C# and uses SOL
- Monitored development progress and ran individual testing

# Flash Multimedia/Animations Designer Bicol University

09/2009 - 10/2009

Legazpi City, Albay

Tasks

 Served as one of the developers of flash-based animation presentations for the school's Quiz Bee Competition event

#### **EDUCATION**

 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering AMA Computer College Manila Campus

05/2015 Manila City